(ｱｻﾞｾﾞﾙ)俺たちの魔都コキｭートスを
滅ぼしたシャリオス１７世は➡
Charioce XVII razed
the demons' capital, Cocytus,
大量の悪魔たちを 無理やり➡
abducted many demons from their homes,
and enslaved them.
この王都に連れてきて
奴隷にしたのだ｡➡
貴様も魔族の血を引くのなら➡
If you have demonkind blood
running through your veins, then use your power for us!
その力を俺たちのために使え！
(ｼｬﾘｵｽ17世)
ようやく会えたな 包帯悪魔｡
We finally meet, Rag Demon!
(ｱｻﾞｾﾞﾙ)シャリオ～～ス！
Charioce!
これが 赤い竜…｡
So this is the red dragon.
ドカーーン！
ドカーン！
(ｱｻﾞｾﾞﾙ)貴様らも うわさぐらいは
聞いたことがあるだろう｡➡
I'm sure even you have heard the rumors
圧倒的な力で
人間どもを蹴散らし➡
about the dragon who routed the humans with
overwhelming power and sent the capital in a panic?
王都を騒がす竜のことを｡
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)何をするつもりだ？
What are you planning on doing?
We will be joining you
in your big day of celebration.
(ｱｻﾞｾﾞﾙ)貴様らの記念日を
俺たちも盛大に祝ってやる｡
行くぞ｡
Let's go.
Rage of Bahamut
Please turn back. Beyond this point--
お止まりください！
ここから先は…｡
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)陛下！ パレードへの参列を
お取りやめくださいませ｡
Your Majesty,
please do not attend the parade.
The demons are involved in suspicious activities.
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)
魔族が不穏な動きをしております｡
それは 包帯悪魔か？
Do you mean the Rag Demon?
Yes.
はい｡
確か➡
I believe his name was Azazel, was it not?
アザゼルといったな｡
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)はっ｡
Yes, My Lord.
Do you not think it would be entertaining?
余興になるとは思わないか？
It was on this day that the demon capital Cocytus fell.
今日は
魔都コキュートスが陥落した日｡
It is a day to celebrate the time
mankind overcame its fear of demons.
人が魔の恐怖を克服した
記念の日だ｡
Let us liven things up
包帯悪魔の首で
花を添えてやろう｡
with the rag demon's head.
陛下！
Your Majesty!
パレードは予定どおり行う｡
The parade will be carried out as scheduled.
If the demons mean to interfere,
悪魔どもが邪魔するなら
皆殺しにするまでだ｡
we will merely slaughter them all.
パン パン！
≪パン！ ヒュー…
パン パン パン！
(ﾆｰﾅ･ﾄﾞﾗﾝｺﾞ)今日のイチ押しは➡
Today's special is a vegetable omelet,
zombie-style!
野菜入りオムレツ
ゾンビ風味だよ｡
昨日の 手羽先の
唐辛子揚げにも負けない➡
A delicious zombie omelet just as good
as yesterday's spicy chicken wings!
おいしい とろっとろの
ゾンビオムレツだよ！
(ﾊﾝｻ)クワッ！
ゾンビ？ 腐ってんのかよ？
Zombie?
-Is it rotten or something?
-Watch it.
(ﾘﾀ)おい！
腐ってなんかないわよ｡
It's not rotten!
It's a legendary flavor over 200 years old.
２００年にわたる伝説の味！
Just try a bite!
一つ 口にしてみて～！
I'll take one, then.
じゃあ 俺 それ１つ｡
じゃあ 俺も｡
Me too.
１つ 下さい｡
俺も１つ くれ｡
-I'll have one, please.
-Could I get one too?
Okay.
Rita, we've got four orders for our zombie omelet.
オッケー｡
リタ！ ゾンビオムレツ➡
４つ 入りました！
はいは～い｡
Okey dokey.
I'm surprised they'd order something with this name.
って よくも まあ
こんな名前で注文するわね｡
どうも！ あっ｡
(２人)ん？
Thank you!
いっ… すみません｡
I'm sorry.
(回想)((楽しかった｡
また会えるといいな))
It was fun.
I hope we can see each other again.
(ﾊﾝｻ)はい どうも！
また来てね｡ はい～｡➡
Here you go, thanks!
Please come again! There you go!
It'd be nice if that handsome guy
from yesterday showed up again.
昨日のイケメン
今日も来るといいですね｡
えっ！ 何？ 誰のこと？
What? Who are you talking about?
They say that what happens twice will happen thrice.
(ﾘﾀ)二度あることは三度ある
っていうでしょう？
ええっ？ 何？ リタまで｡
Not you too, Rita.
腕相撲 前夜祭
そして 今日ですよ！➡
The arm wrestling, last night's festival,
and now today.
クワ～ クワッ クワッ クワッ！
(ﾘﾀ)ふふふふっ｡
You're not making any sense.
意味分かんない｡
ご注文 伺います！
Could I take your orders?
へっ？ さっき言ったけど｡
えっ？ あっ はい ごめんなさい！
We already gave our order.
Right! Sorry about that!
やっぱり
昨日 なんかあったのかもね｡
I wonder if something did happen yesterday.
Perhaps she took a step towards adulthood.
大人の階段を
上がってしまったんですクワァね｡
ふ～ん｡
クワッ？
A step towards adulthood.
大人の階段を
駆け上がったあのころ…｡
I remember a time like that.
It brings back so many memories.
懐かしいわね｡
いつの話ですクワァ？
When are you talking about?
A very
とても遠い… 昔の話よ｡
long time ago.
クワァ～｡
いらっしゃい いらっしゃい！
Welcome, welcome!
ふわふわで とろとろの
ゾンビオムレツ おいしいよ！
We've got fluffy, delicious zombie omelets
that will melt in your mouth!
ゾンビだからってビビんないで
食べてみて！ ほらほら～｡
Don't be scared because of the name!
Just try them!
Come on, come on!
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)お前 妙な力
持ってるらしいじゃねぇか｡
I hear you have an unusual power.
Can you really not talk?
ほんとに しゃべれねぇのか？
なんで いつも笑ってんだ？
Why are you always smiling?
Actually, you look like someone.
つぅか お前 誰かに似てんなぁ｡
≪(ｿﾌｨｴﾙ)何をしている？
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)うわぁ～！➡
What are you doing?
Don't sneak up on me!
脅かすんじゃねぇ！
(ｿﾌｨｴﾙ)その後 どうだ？
So any news since we last spoke?
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)えっ？ いや 何も…｡
No, nothing.
(ｿﾌｨｴﾙ)はぁ～｡ そうか｡
I see.
こちらも進展がなくてな｡
Nothing new has happened on my end either.
It's been five days since I
came down to the lower world.
下界に来て
５日もたつというのに…｡
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)それは ご苦労なこった｡
お前も大変だな｡➡
Sorry to hear that!
Sounds like things have been tough.
あはははっ！ あ～はははっ…｡
Who is that child?
その子供は なんだ？
あはっ… えっ？ えっ？ あっ｡
Oh, this one?
あっ… こ… こいつは あれだよ
ただの悪魔のガキだ｡➡
Just some demon kid, that's all.
I just picked the kid off the street
and put the brat to work.
道端で拾って 働かせてるだけだ｡
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)そ… そうだ！ お前 ほら➡
Oh, right!
Hey, get back to work already!
屋台の手伝い
サボってんじゃねぇよ バカ野郎｡
You idiot.
早く ほら ニーナんとこ
い… 行ってこい｡ なっ？
Now go over to Nina, okay?
あっ…｡
ふん…｡
I will be back.
また来る｡
Why didn't you tell her the truth?
≪(ﾊﾝｻ)なぜ言わないんですクワァ
本当のことを！
おめぇも脅かすなよ バカ！
Don't sneak up on me either, idiot!
Is it because Nina
would be sad if Mugaro went away?
ムガロがいなくなると ニーナが
悲しむクワァらですクワァ？
No!
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)ち… 違ぇよ！
So you would have no problem
if I went and told Lady Sofiel?
じゃあ 私が ソフィエル様に
言ってもいいですね？
About the color of the child's eyes?
あの子の瞳の色を｡
やめろ｡
クワッ？
Don't.
なぜですクワァ？
そしたら 神界に帰れるのですよ！
Why not? Then we would be able
to return to heaven!
嫌な予感がする｡
I have a bad feeling about it.
What do you mean by that?
(ﾊﾝｻ)
それ どういう意味ですクワァ？
Don't you think it's messed up that the Orleans Knights
aren't in the parade?
オルレアン騎士団が
パレードに出ないって➡
おかしくないっすか？
まっ しかたないっすかね｡
I guess that's just how things go.
最近 俺たち
なんの手柄も立ててないし｡➡
We haven't exactly accomplished much lately.
あっ 団長だ｡
It's the captain!
(ﾃﾞｨｱｽ)
団長！ 何かあったのですか？
Captain! Has something happened?
The demons are scheming something.
悪魔たちが 何か たくらんでいる｡
(２人)えっ｡
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)
正午には パレードの開始だ｡➡
The parade will commence at noon.
We have to find and stop them before then!
それまでに捜して
取り押さえなければ｡
まさか ヤツらの狙いは…｡
You don't think they're after...
What are you talking about?
何なんすか？ それ｡
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)急ごう！
-Let us hurry!
-Alessand!
(ﾃﾞｨｱｽ)アレサンド！
あっ ちょっと！
Wait! Could you explain?
ちゃんと…｡ なんすか？
What's going on?
Why is she not coming?
なぜ来ない…｡
パレードって どんなだろうね？
I wonder what the parade is like.
ムガロちゃん 見たことある？
Have you seen it before?
You can't see anything from here.
ここじゃ見えないね｡
I can't see!
見えないよ～！
Rage of Bahamut
ヒュー… パン パン パン パン！
Damn it.
パン パン パン パン！
We managed to get everything ready on our end.
(悪魔)こちらは 問題なく整った｡
How did it go with you?
(ﾀﾞﾝﾃ)そっちはどうだ？
(ﾍﾞﾙﾌｪｺﾞｰﾙ)問題ないわ｡
It wasn't a problem.
(ﾀﾞﾝﾃ)よし 合図を待て｡
Good. Wait for the signal, then.
わあ～ よく見える！
I've got a good view now!
Heh, the king's already come and gone.
(ﾊﾟﾝ屋)もう 王様は
先 行っちゃったけどな｡
私 王様は別にいい｡
(ﾊﾟﾝ屋)えっ？
I don't really care about the king.
-What?
-The parade is so cool!
パレード かっこいい～！
あれ？
どうした？
-What's wrong?
-Nina?
ニーナ？ ん？ ん？
ちょっ ちょっ… お～い！
Hey!
痛っ！ 何すんの… うっ！
What's the big idea?
Why did you not show up
where we were supposed to meet?
貴様 なぜ約束の場所に来ない？
だって パレード見てたんだもん｡
Because I was watching the parade!
Just come! We're out of time!
とにかく来い！ もう時間がない！
Mugaro!
ムガロちゃん！
助けて ムガロちゃん｡
Help me, Mugaro.
ムガロ!?
Mugaro?
Is that you, Mugaro?
(ｱｻﾞｾﾞﾙ)ムガロなのか？
そうだよ｡ かわいいでしょ｡
That's right. She's cute, isn't she?
ドカーン！
ドカン ドカン ドカン！
(市民たち)きゃあ～！
あっ… しまった｡
Damn it.
Send the carriage back to the palace.
(隊長)王宮まで 馬車を戻せ｡
他の兵も 一刻も早く戻るんだ｡
The other soldiers
should get back immediately as well.
≫無駄だ｡
It's no use.
四方の退路は
全て封鎖されている｡
All of our escape paths have been cut off.
We will not be able to easily return to the palace.
容易に王宮へは戻れまい｡
That means that
ここが 魔族どもとの➡
this is where we battle the demons.
決戦の地ということだ｡
ねえ 今の音 何？
Hey, what was that noise?
What are you doing?
何してんの？
あっ…｡
(ｱｻﾞｾﾞﾙ)んっ！
はい？
Yes?
Seriously, what are you doing?
だから 何してんの？
ちっ しかたない｡
I have no other choice.
んんっ！
ドォーン！
なぜ 竜にならん!?
Why are you not transforming?
えっ？
いや よく分かんないけど…➡
I'm not really sure why,
but my heart isn't racing at all.
なんか
全然ドキドキしないんだよね｡
-The red dragon?
-There are no reports yet.
(ﾀﾞﾝﾃ)赤い竜は？
(悪魔)まだ報告はない｡
They should have acted by now.
(ﾀﾞﾝﾃ)遅いな｡
(悪魔)どうする？
What do we do?
It's weird, isn't it?
おっかしいよね～｡
I was so excited just the other day.
この前まで
あんなにドキドキしたのに｡
Oh, do you think this is because
I've experienced true love?
あっれ～？
これって もしかして➡
本当の恋をしたからかなぁ？
あはははっ！
I have to stop the attack.
(ｱｻﾞｾﾞﾙ)作戦を止めなければ｡
あぁ～ん もう 恋…｡
恋～ ふふっ！
Love!
あっ アザゼル どこ行くんだろ？
I wonder where Azazel is going.
Honestly, what is with that guy?
まったく…｡ なんだ？ あいつ｡
Hurry! Rescue the survivors!
(兵士)生存者の救出を急げ！
All free hands secure the area around the king!
手の空いた者は
シャリオス王の周りを固めろ！
んん…｡
(悪魔)どうする!?
What do we do?
(ﾍﾞﾙﾌｪｺﾞｰﾙ)
これ以上 兵が増えると まずいわ｡
We won't be able to take on any more reinforcements.
Did Azazel betray us?
(悪魔)アザゼルめ 裏切ったのか！
はっ… そんな！
No.
We have no other choice
than to wait for the red dragon.
(ﾀﾞﾝﾃ)今は 赤い竜を待つしかない｡
ここで動いたところで…｡
-If we were to move--
-You there!
≫そこの者！
(３人)あっ！
来い｡
Get over here.
They are demon rebels.
そいつらは 悪魔の反逆者だ｡
Cut off their heads.
首をはねよ｡
(３人)あっ…｡
-Not yet.
-Let go of me!
(ﾀﾞﾝﾃ)まだだ｡
(悪魔)放せ｡
(兵士たち)うおぉ～！
ドォーン！
(兵士たち)うわっ！
シュン シュン シュン！
ドォン ドォン ドォン！
(兵士)ぐわっ！
(兵士たち)うおぉ～！ ぐわっ！
ピシュン！ ピシュン！
Damn it.
何が起きたんだろう？
ねえ ムガロちゃん➡
What happened?
Hey, Mugaro...
あっ… ムガロちゃん？
ドォーン！
Damn it!
(悪魔)くそっ！
なぜ 赤い竜は来ない!?➡
Where is the red dragon?
アザゼルは何を…｡
はっ！
What is Azazel--
ドスッ！
ぐあっ！
(悪魔)ぐおっ！
ぐおっ！
(ﾀﾞﾝﾃ)ふん！
(兵士)ぐわっ！
ふん！
(兵士)うっ！
グアァーー！
≫ドスッ！
あっ…｡
アザゼル様！
Lord Azazel!
遅かったな｡
Finally.
It is time we settle this once and for all.
いいかげんに
決着をつけようではないか｡
It's okay, it's okay
I cast the usual spell
Stagnation, stagnation
My words and heart are at odds
Default
I've taken all the paint
And mixed up all the colors
Until you're left with me
So fragile
Yet strong
Close to overflowing
But not spilling
Because I'm incomplete
I won't amount to much
This is just a good luck charm
I'm not asking for your help
I was just clinging to you
Let's end it all today
I'm done living this pointless life
I've taken my last pointless breath
To whom it may concern, see ya and goodbye
I killed the person I was yesterday
A new morning is coming
(ﾀﾞﾝﾃ)赤い竜はどうした？
What happened to the red dragon?
(ﾀﾞﾝﾃ)ふっ お前を信じた俺たちが
バカだったな｡
We were fools to have trusted you.
I will draw them to me.
俺がヤツらを引き付ける｡
むちゃです！
You can't!
(ｱｻﾞｾﾞﾙ)お前たちは生きろ！
I want you to live!
今だ！
Now!
ドカッ！
(ｱｻﾞｾﾞﾙ)そやっ！
(隊長)一人も逃すな！
Don't let a single one get away!
はっ！ ダンテ…｡
Dante...
ドゴン‼
-This is Gabriel
-and Sofiel.
We are Gods!
Your hair is so silky and so well maintained
-You are gorgeous as usual, Lord Gabriel.
-Oh my oh my...
Next time on Rage of Bahamut:
Virgin Soul, "The Day of Defeat."
-Is this how it's done?
-We are Gods!
Baha Soul!!
Lord Azazel,
what are you looking at?
The future.